AARON ARGUELLES: FRONT-END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Wellsville, UT | 435-994-4203 | arguelles.business@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Front-End Software Developer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS/SCSS, API implementing, Node.JS, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap and Tailwind. Experience in team and leadership roles provides an advantage in discovering and implementing solutions to problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, React, Astro, Handlebars.js, TypeScript, Next.js

Backend: Node.js, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Strapi

Tools: BigCommerce, Stencil, DigitalOcean, Visual Studio Code, ClickUp, Figma, Node Package Manager, Yarn,

Git, GitHub, ADA/WCAG Compliance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Malouf Companies

Logan, UT

03/2024 - Present

Web Developer 1 Took on the role of lead developer for multiple website redesigns and directed team to specific tasks.

- Worked cross-functionally with design and content departments to develop user interfaces, reusable components, and changes to data entry.
- Partnered with marketing and sales teams to translate business objectives into actionable code.
- Created new projects from scratch and checked them into source control/repositories with safeguards to protect the main branch.
- Debugged sites/applications and implemented fixes.
- Possessed knowledge of web performance issues, causes, and remediation.
- Worked with SPA and MPA sites/apps/projects.

Jr. Web Developer

09/2023 - 03/2024

- Completed development tasks according to a sprint schedule.
- Wrote code compliant with ADA/WCAG AA 2.2+.
- Collaborated with teammates to create implementation plans and best practices.
- Effectively prioritized work to accommodate ad-hoc support to internal clients.
- Contributed quality code as well as documentation.
- Participated in code reviews, team and new employee trainings, testing, and overall morale.
- Became proficient with using BigCommerce, an eCommerce platform.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Online 04/2023 - 09/2023

Certificate, Software Engineering

Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful API's, algorithms, and data structures.

Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.